Alex Jordan

Software Developer

London, UK

▼ jordan.alex.g@gmail.com

in alexandrejordan

Summary

I'm a London-based software engineer with a background in product management and a passion for creating and delivering user-centric products. I feel most confident coding in TypeScript but I also have experience in Python and Java. I have dabbled in C, Lua, and Ruby in side projects.

I'm motivated by big goals and clear missions. I do my best work in fast-paced environments where I can take on interesting challenges, make a quick impact, and keep growing.

Skills

Typescript • React •

React Native • Agile •

Product Leadership • HTML •

CSS • Python • Data Analysis •

SOL • Node

Education

University of British Columbia,

BA - Political Science & Philosophy 2008 – 2012 | Vancouver, Canada

Languages

English • French

Interests

Skiing • Reading • Films • Music

Professional Experience

Software Engineer, Holistic Al

Sep 2022 - present | London, UK

- Led the (front-end) development of several applications from inception, including a platform for large language model (LLM) auditing and monitoring, and a system to audit Automated Environmental Decision Tools (AEDT) for NYC Local Law 144.
- Refactored and improved existing projects, modularizing and simplifying the code to improve readability and maintainability.
- Contributed to multiple existing back-end projects, primarily using TypeScript, with additional experience in Java and Python.

Software Engineer, *Clim8*

Dec 2021 - Jul 2022 | London, UK

- Delivered a wide range of Android and iOS app features including charting historical performance data, ISA transfer functionality, Junior ISA accounts (risk/suitability assessment, product explanation, etc.), and a fairly complex account closure flow.
- Mostly focused on using React Native and TypeScript to create new features, tested with Jest and React Native Testing Library.

Junior Full Stack Developer, _nology

Jan 2021 - Nov 2021 | London, UK

- Completed a 12-week boot camp to learn web development technologies
- Seconded to Sugar (add-sugar.io) for 6 months as a Junior Developer where I built their internal credit management portal using React, Typescript, and Python, using AWS Lambda functions.

Product Manager, Pass the Keys

Jan 2019 – Jan 2021 | London, UK

- Introduced Agile methodologies to shorten the release cycle for dev team
- Led Engineering team with ROI exceeding 150% within a year on multiple features including Pricing optimization algorithms, Pricing adjustment tools, Professional Photography upload tools
- Taught myself SQL and Python for data analysis to ensure that product decisions could be data-backed

Product Manager, Big Sofa Technologies

Aug 2016 - Dec 2018 | London, UK

- Initiated and scoped breakdown of monolith app into microservices to increase maintainability and speed up future development
- Led two dedicated teams with competing deadlines to deliver on time and within budget